<?xml version="1.0"?>
<block>
  <name>Frame Synchronizer</name>
  <key>blocksat_frame_synchronizer_cc</key>
  <category>[Blockstream Satellite]/Synchronizers</category>
  <import>import blocksat</import>
  <make>blocksat.frame_synchronizer_cc(
  $preamble_syms,
  $frame_len,
  $M,
  $n_success_to_lock,
  $en_eq,
  $en_phase_corr,
  $verbose)</make>
  <callback>get_mag_pmf_peak()</callback>
  <callback>get_state()</callback>
  <param>
    <name>Preamble Symbols</name>
    <key>preamble_syms</key>
    <type>complex_vector</type>
  </param>
  <param>
    <name>Frame Length</name>
    <key>frame_len</key>
    <type>int</type>
  </param>
  <param>
    <name>Constellation Order</name>
    <key>M</key>
    <value>2</value>
    <type>int</type>
    <hide>none</hide>
    <option>
      <name>2 (BPSK)</name>
      <key>2</key>
    </option>
    <option>
      <name>4 (QPSK)</name>
      <key>4</key>
    </option>
  </param>
  <param>
    <name>Success to Lock</name>
    <key>n_success_to_lock</key>
    <type>int</type>
  </param>
  <param>
    <name>Gain Scaling</name>
    <key>en_eq</key>
    <type>bool</type>
    <option>
      <name>Disabled</name>
      <key>False</key>
    </option>
    <option>
      <name>Enabled</name>
      <key>True</key>
    </option>
  </param>
  <param>
    <name>Phase Correction</name>
    <key>en_phase_corr</key>
    <type>bool</type>
    <option>
      <name>Disabled</name>
      <key>False</key>
    </option>
    <option>
      <name>Enabled</name>
      <key>True</key>
    </option>
  </param>
  <param>
    <name>Verbose</name>
    <key>verbose</key>
    <type>bool</type>
  </param>
  <sink>
    <name>in</name>
    <type>complex</type>
    <vlen>1</vlen>
  </sink>
  <source>
    <name>out</name>
    <type>complex</type>
    <vlen>1</vlen>
  </source>
  <source>
    <name>pmf_out</name>
    <type>complex</type>
    <vlen>1</vlen>
    <optional>1</optional>
  </source>
  <doc>Continuous-transmission Correlation-based Frame Synchronization


Frame synchronization algorithm that relies on a filter matched to the \
preamble, known as "preamble matched filter" (PMF) in order to compute the \
cross-correlation between the received symbols and the preamble symbols known \
a priori.

The block should be configured with a vector of preamble symbols that presents \
good correlation performance, namely a sequence of symbols that is highly \
correlated at lag 0 and presents negligible correlation for all other lags. \
For example, a Barker code sequence.

Internally the cross-correlation is constantly computed and the peaks are \
inspected. All peaks exceeding the "Peak Detection Threshold" parameter are \
deemed as peaks, but the internal logic searches for the highest peak in case \
there are multiple peaks for one frame.\

The block keeps track of a sequence of peaks and, because it is configured \
with the frame length (given by both the preamble and payload lengths), it is \
able to compare whether the interval between detected peaks matches the \
expected interval (assuming continuous transmission). Once this is true for \
sufficiently long, the block infers that frame synchronization has been \
acquired.

Finally, once frame synchronization lock is acquired, the block starts to \
output symbols. It can be configured either to 1) output both preamble and \
payload symbols or 2) solely payload symbols. The former alternative is used \
when the downstream blocks rely on the preamble for any data-aided processing, \
such as data-aided carrier phase correction.

Note #1: \
An important remark is that the PMF can also be used for channel estimation. \
In fact, a single-tap channel estimator based on least-squares gives the exact \
same solution as the result of the peak yielded by the PMF. Nevertheless, \
note that, because there may be carrier frequency or phase offset affecting \
the incoming symbols, this channel estimation can be unreliable in terms of \
phase, although it may still be useful in order to obtain the channel gain. \
Hence, when the "Single-tap Equalization" parameter is enabled, only magnitude \
(channel gain) equalization is performed.

Note #2: \
When observing the complex-valued PMF peak, it can be seen that the peak may \
be rotated in the complex plane. For example, when using two-dimensional \
preamble symbols, the peak may result in the real component and be positive \
(non-rotated case), but it may also appear for instance in the imaginary \
component as a negative peak (due to rotation). This rotation is inspected \
internally and can be used for phase correction, if the "Phase Correction" \
parameter is enabled.

</doc>
</block>
